A Guide to the Harry F. Byrd Jr. Papers
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #10320
Harry F. Byrd, Jr. Papers ca. 1958-1974
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10320
ca. 134,000 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access to the Harry F. Byrd, Jr., Papers is controlled by the Honorable Harry F. Byrd, Jr. An applicant for access who is not associated with the University of Virginia must furnish to the Director of Special Collections a brief description of his academic or other qualifications, a summary of his research project, and a description of any projected publication that might make use of material from, or material derived from, the Harry F. Byrd, Jr., Papers. The Director of Special Collections will contact Senator Byrd and will notify the applicant of the Senator's decision.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the Library by Harry F. Byrd, Jr. of Winchester, Virginia, on February 21, 1979.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of ca. 134,000 items (268 Hollinger boxes and 30 cubics, ca. 150 linear feet) ca. 1958-1974, and contains papers pertaining to the political career of Harry F. Byrd, Jr.of Winchester, Virginia, in the United States Senate, and papers of the Byrd family, and includes campaign material, legislative files, speeches, correspondence, miscellaneous and topical files, constituent and fan mail, and daily carbons.
Decisions concerning the processing and retention of individual files were made by the Curator based upon the recommendations in
Records Management Handbook for United States Senators and Their Repositories
by Karen Dawley Paul, Archivist Senate Historical Office.
The first series contains the campaign files for the 1966 Democratic Primary and Senatorial Election, and the 1970 Senatorial Race. Some of the more outstanding correspondents in this series are noted in the box listing.
Senator Byrd's speeches and statements comprise the second series and include typed manuscripts of speeches, electrostatic copies of manuscript and printed speeches, copies of the
Congressional Record
containing speeches or statements by Byrd, and news releases concerning speeches. A complete typed list of individual speeches can be found in a spring-back binder in Box 61.
The third and largest series is composed of Senator Byrd's legislative files which are listed alphabetically in the box listing by folder heading and are arranged in reverse chronological order. Whenever possible the original folder heading was retained. Some topics, such as Welfare, which a researcher might expect to find under Health, Education, and Welfare, generated so much material that the office simply filed the material under Welfare. It is best to check as many alternate headings as possible to ensure finding a particular subject. Senator Byrd served on the Agriculture and Forestry Committee, the Armed Services Committee, and the Committee on Finance, so there are a considerable number of related files in this collection.
The fourth series contains correspondence with individual politicians both on the national and state level, personal correspondence, Byrd familycorrespondence, Byrd business correspondence, and correspondence with other Senators and Congressmen. These folders are arranged alphabetically by the name of correspondent or type of correspondence.
Miscellaneous and non-legislative topical files were placed in series five and arranged alphabetically by subject. This series includes the following types of material: acceptances of invitations to speak, participation in the Alfalfa Club and Alibi Club, the Apple Blossom Festival, the Bicentennial Commission, various Democratic Party organizations, Media folders, Special Committees on which Byrd served, the Tax Foundation, and information gathering trips to Asia, Central America, and the Middle East.
The sixth series consisting of chronological constituent and fan mail was determined to be an ideal candidate for systematic sampling due to the large amounts of similiar material in this series and its non- topical arrangement. A systematic sample is one in which the sample elements are picked by their location within the total population. Ten percent of the total number of constituent letters was determined to be a statistically valid sample size. The procedure for sampling was as follows: the constituent files were arranged in chronological order, every tenth letter was pulled from the files and retained, and the remainder was destroyed. Thus out of a total of 16,340 constituent letters, a ten percent sample or 1,634 letters were kept. Any large chronological gaps in the constituent mail sample were present in the original arrangement and are not a result of the sampling procedure. This same procedure was used for the fan mail.
The last series consists of thirty cubics of daily carbons which this department hopes to microfilm at some future date. The listing of audiotapes and oversize material follows the carbons and can be found in this guide.
Organization
This collection is arranged in seven series and generally is in reverse chronological order; exceptions include the speech series and the constituent and fan mail samples series. The series are: Series I: Campaign Files, Subseries A: 1966 Election, 1. District Files (Boxes 1-14) and 2. Management Files (Boxes 15-25), Subseries B: 1970 Election, 1. District Files (Boxes 26-41), 2. Management Files (Boxes 41-49), and 3. Publicity Files (Boxes 50-51); Series II: Speeches (Boxes 52-61); Series III: Legislative Files, Subseries A: General (Boxes 62-224), Subseries B: Senate Committees (Boxes 225-226); Series IV: Correspondence (Boxes 227-239); Series V: Miscellaneous & Topical Files (Boxes 240-259); and Series VI: Chronological Constituent & Fan Mail (Boxes 260-266).
Container List
- Series I: Campaign Files
  - Subseries A: 1966 Election
    - 1). District Files
      - First District
        - Gloucester County, 1966 Jan-Nov (Box Box 1)
        - Hampton, 1966 Jan-Dec (Box Box 1)
        - James City County, 1966 Feb-Nov (Box Box 1)
        - Mathews County, 1966 Feb-Nov (Box Box 1)
        - Middlesex County, 1966 Jan-Dec (Box Box 1)
        - Newport News, 1966 Jan-Dec (Box Box 1)
        - Northampton County, 1966 Jan-Nov (Box Box 1)
        - Virginia Beach, 1965 Dec-1966 Dec (Box Box 1)
        - Williamsburg, 1966 Jan-Dec (Box Box 1)
        - York County, 1966 Feb-Dec (Box Box 1)
      - Second District
        - Norfolk, 1965 Nov-1966 Dec; (4 folders) (Box Box 2)
        - Portsmouth, 1965 Nov-1966 Dec (Box Box 2)
      - Third District
        - Chesterfield County, 1966 Jan-Dec (Box Box 2)
        - Henrico County, 1966 Feb-Dec (Box Box 2)
        - Richmond - A-Be, 1965 Nov-1966 Dec (Box Box 2)
        - Richmond - Bi-Q, 1965 Nov-1967 Jan; (7 folders) (Box Box 3)
        - Richmond - R-Z, 1965 Nov-1967 Jan; (3 folders) (Box Box 4)
      - Fourth District
        - Amelia County, 1965 Dec-1966 Nov (Box Box 4)
        - Appomattox and Buckingham Counties, 1966 Mar-Nov (Box Box 4)
        - Chesapeake, 1965 Dec-1966 Dec (Box Box 4)
        - Colonial Heights, 1966 Jan-Jul (Box Box 4)
        - Cumberland and Dinwiddie Counties, 1966 Mar-Dec (Box Box 4)
        - Franklin, 1965 Nov-1966 Dec (Box Box 4)
        - Greensville County, 1965 Dec-1966 Nov (Box Box 5)
        - Hopewell, 1965 Dec-1966 Dec (Box Box 5)
        - Isle of Wight County, 1965 Nov-1966 Oct (Box Box 5)
        - Lunenburg County, 1965 Nov-1966 Oct (Box Box 5)
        - Nansemond and Nottoway Counties, 1965 Nov-1966 Oct (Box Box 5)
        - Petersburg, 1965 Nov-1966 Dec (Box Box 5)
        - Powhatan County, 1965 Nov-1966 Oct (Box Box 5)
        - Prince Edward and Prince George Counties, 1965 Nov-1966 Nov (Box Box 5)
        - Southampton County, 1965 Dec-1966 Dec (Box Box 5)
        - Suffolk, 1965 Nov-1966 Nov (Box Box 5)
        - Surry and Sussex Counties, 1965 Nov-1966 Jul (Box Box 5)
      - Fifth District
        - Brunswick County, 1966 Feb-Oct (Box Box 6)
        - Campbell, Carroll, and Charlotte Counties, 1966 Jan-Dec (Box Box 6)
        - Danville, 1966 Jan-Nov (Box Box 6)
        - Franklin County, 1966 Jan-Sep (Box Box 6)
        - Galax, 1966 Jan-Nov (Box Box 6)
        - Grayson, Halifax, and Henry Counties, 1965 Nov-1966 Dec (Box Box 6)
        - Martinsville, 1966 Jan-Dec (Box Box 6)
        - Mecklenburg County, 1965 Nov-1966 Nov (Box Box 6)
        - Patrick and Pittsylvania Counties, 1965 Nov-1966 Aug (Box Box 6)
        - South Boston, 1966 Jan-Dec (Box Box 6)
      - Sixth District
        - Alleghany, Amherst, Bedford, and Botetourt Counties, 1965 Nov-1966 Oct (Box Box 7)
        - Clifton Forge, 1966 Jan-Dec (Box Box 7)
        - Covington, 1966 Jan-Nov (Box Box 7)
        - Craig and Floyd Counties, 1966 Feb-Dec (Box Box 7)
        - Lynchburg, 1965 Nov-1966 Nov; (2 folders) (Box Box 7)
        - Montgomery and Nelson Counties, 1965 Dec-1966 Nov (Box Box 7)
        - Radford, 1965 Nov-1966 Dec (Box Box 7)
        - Roanoke, City of, 1965 Nov-1966 Dec; (3 folders) (Box Box 8)
        - Roanoke County, 1966 Jan-Dec (Box Box 8)
      - Seventh District
        - Albemarle, Augusta, and Bath Counties, 1965 Dec-1966 Dec (Box Box 8)
        - Buena Vista, 1965 Nov-1966 Aug (Box Box 8)
        - Charlottesville, 1965 Nov-1966 Dec; (2 folders) (Box Box 8)
        - Clarke County, 1965 Mar-1967 Jan (Box Box 9)
        - Culpeper County, 1965 Nov-1966 Nov (Box Box 9)
        - Fluvanna, Frederick, Greene, and Highland Counties, 1965 Nov-1967 Jan (Box Box 9)
        - Harrisonburg, 1965 Nov-1966 Nov (Box Box 9)
        - Madison, Orange, and Page Counties, 1965 Nov-1966 Dec (Box Box 9)
        - Rappahannock and Rockbridge Counties, 1965 Nov-1966 Nov (Box Box 9)
        - Rockingham County, 1965 Nov-1966 Nov (Box Box 10)
        - Shenandoah County, 1965 Nov-1966 Dec (Box Box 10)
        - Staunton, 1965 Nov-1966 Dec (Box Box 10)
        - Warren County, 1965 Nov-1966 Dec (Box Box 10)
        - Waynesboro, 1966 Jan-Dec (Box Box 10)
        - Winchester - A-R, 1965 Nov-1966 Nov; (3 folders) (Box Box 10)
        - Winchester - S-Z, 1965 Nov-1966 Nov (Box Box 11)
      - Eighth District
        - Caroline, Charles City, and Essex Counties, 1965 Nov-1966 Nov (Box Box 11)
        - Fauquier County, 1965 Nov-1966 Oct (Box Box 11)
        - Fredericksburg, 1965 Nov-1966 Oct (Box Box 11)
        - Goochland and Hanover Counties, 1965 Nov-1966 Dec (Box Box 11)
        - King & Queen, King George, King William, and Lancaster Counties, 1965 Nov-1966 Dec (Box Box 11)
        - Loudoun and Louisa Counties, 1965 Nov-1966 Nov (Box Box 11)
        - New Kent, Northumberland, and Prince William Counties, 1965 Nov-1966 Oct (Box Box 12)
        - Richmond, Spottsylvania, Stafford, and Westmoreland Counties, 1965 Nov-1966 Dec (Box Box 12)
      - Ninth District
        - Bland County, 1966 Apr-Dec (Box Box 12)
        - Bristol, 1965 Nov-1966 Dec (Box Box 12)
        - Buchanan, Dickenson, Giles, and Lee Counties, 1965 Nov-1966 Dec (Box Box 12)
        - Norton, 1965 Nov-1966 Dec (Box Box 12)
        - Pulaski, Russell, Scott, and Smyth Counties, 1965 Nov-1966 Dec (Box Box 12)
        - Tazewell and Washington Counties, 1966 Feb-Nov (Box Box 12)
        - Wise and Wythe Counties, 1965 Nov-1966 Dec (Box Box 12)
      - Tenth District
        - Alexandria, 1965 Nov-1966 Dec; (4 folders) (Box Box 13)
        - Arlington County, 1965 Nov-1966 Nov; (3 folders) (Box Box 13)
        - Arlington County - General, 1966 (Box Box 14)
        - Fairfax County, 1965 Nov-1966 Dec; (3 folders) (Box Box 14)
        - Falls Church, 1965 Nov-1966 Nov (Box Box 14)
    - 2). Management Files
      - Address Corrections - Providence Magisterial District - 8th District, 1966 (Box Box 15)
      - Biography & Quotations of Harry F. Byrd, Jr., 1965-1966 (Box Box 15)
      - Blackburn, Hon. Joseph E., 1966 (Box Box 15)
      - Bolling, Mrs. A. Stuart, 1966 (Box Box 15)
      - Campaign Advertising, 1966-1967; (2 folders) (Box Box 15)
      - Campaign Expenditure Reporting, 1966 (Box Box 15)
      - Campaign Lists, 1965-1967, n.d.; (2 folders) (Box Box 15)
      - Campaign Literature, 1966 (Box Box 15)
      - Campaign Managers and Chairmen - Districts 1-6, 1965-1966; (7 folders) (Box Box 15-A)
      - Campaign Managers and Chairmen - Districts 7-10, 1965-1966; (7 folders) (Box Box 16)
      - Campaign Petitions - Districts 1-6, 1966; (6 folders) (Box Box 17)
      - Campaign Petitions - Districts 7-10, 1966; (6 folders) (Box Box 18)
      - Congratulation Letters: Districts 1-7, 1966 Nov; (8 folders) (Box Box 19)
      - Congratulation Letters: Districts 8-10, 1966 Nov-Dec; (2 folders) (Box Box 20)
      - Congratulation Letters - Out-of-State: A-H, 1965-1966; (6 folders) (Box Box 20)
        Correspondents include: Bernard M. Baruch, Jr.; Birch Bayh; Edmund G. Brown; Mrs. Richard E. Byrd (Marie); Douglas Fairbanks, Jr.; Melville Bell Grosvenor; George B. Hartzog, Jr.; J. Edgar Hoover
      - Congratulation Letters - Out-of-State: J-Z, 1965-1966; (7 folders) (Box Box 21)
        Correspondents include: Bernard Kilgore; David Rockefeller; and John A. Volpe
      - Congratulation Letters: VIP File - A-Z, 1966 Nov-Dec; (5 folders) (Box Box 22)
        Correspondents include: Birch Bayh; Richard E. Byrd, Jr.; Mortimer M. Caplin; Douglas Fairbanks, Jr. (telegram); J. Edgar Hoover; Hubert Humphrey; Lyndon B. Johnson; Walter Mondale (telegram); Edmund S. Muskie; Eugene McCarthy; Adam Clayton Powell
      - Conservative Party Telecast, 1966 Oct 30 (Box Box 22)
      - Correspondence re the Committee Assignments of Members of the Virginia General Assembly, 1965 Nov-Dec (Box Box 22)
      - Democratic National & State Central Committees, 1965-1967 (Box Box 22)
      - Finance Committee Luncheon, 1966 Mar-Jun (Box Box 22)
      - Finance Committee Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1966 Apr-Dec (Box Box 22)
      - Finance Committee Miscellaneous Files, 1966 Jan-Oct; (2 folders) (Box Box 22)
      - Form Letters, 1965-1966 (Box Box 22)
      - Invitations Accepted, 1966-1967 (Box Box 23)
      - Lists of Registered Voters - 8th & 10th Districts, 1966; (7 folders) (Box Box 23)
      - Miscellaneous, 1966 (Box Box 23-A)
      - Press Releases & Drafts, 1965-1966 (Box Box 23-A)
      - Radio & Television Contracts, 1966 (Box Box 23-A)
      - Requests for Assistance, 1966 (Box Box 23-A)
      - Richmond Campaign Headquarters, 1966 Mar-Jul (Box Box 23-A)
      - Tabloid issue re Harry F. Byrd, Jr. printed by the Winchester Evening Star, 1966 (Box Box 24)
      - Thank You Letters for Contributions, 1966 Feb 28-Jun 22; (5 folders) (Box Box 24)
      - Thank You Letters for Contributions, 1966 Jun 23-Dec; (7 folders) (Box Box 25)
      - Votes Cast in the Virginia General Election for Members of the Senate and House of Delegates, 1965 Nov 2 (Box Box 25)
  - Subseries B: 1970 Election
    - 1). District Files
      - First District
        - Accomac County, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 26)
        - Gloucester, James City, and Mathews Counties, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 26)
        - Hampton, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 26)
        - Middlesex and Northampton Counties, 1970 Mar-Oct (Box Box 26)
        - Newport News, 1970 Mar-Nov; (2 folders) (Box Box 26)
        - Virginia Beach, 1970 Mar-Nov; (2 folders) (Box Box 27)
        - Williamsburg, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 27)
        - York County, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 27)
      - Second District
        - Norfolk, 1970 Mar-Dec; (4 folders) (Box Box 27)
        - Portsmouth, 1970 Mar-Nov; (3 folders) (Box Box 28)
      - Third District
        - Chesterfield County, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 28)
        - Henrico County, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 28)
        - Richmond - A-C, 1970 Mar-Nov; (4 folders) (Box Box 28)
        - Richmond - D-O, 1970 Mar-Nov; (6 folders) (Box Box 29)
        - Richmond - P-Z, 1970 Mar-Nov; (7 folders) (Box Box 30)
      - Fourth District
        - Amelia, Appomattox, Buckingham, Cumberland, and Dinwiddie Counties, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 31)
        - Chesapeake, 1970 Mar-Nov; (2 folders) (Box Box 31)
        - Colonial Heights, 1970 Mar-Oct (Box Box 31)
        - Emporia and Franklin Cities, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 31)
        - Greensville County, 1970 Mar (Box Box 31)
        - Hopewell, 1970 Mar-Dec (Box Box 31)
        - Isle of Wight, Lunenburg, Nansemond, and Nottoway Counties, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 31)
        - Petersburg, 1970 Mar-Oct (Box Box 31)
        - Powhatan, Prince Edward, and Prince George Counties, 1970 Mar-Oct (Box Box 32)
        - Southampton, Surry, and Sussex Counties, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 32)
        - Suffolk, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 32)
      - Fifth District
        - Brunswick, Campbell, Carroll, and Charlotte Counties, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 32)
        - Danville, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 32)
        - Franklin and Grayson Counties, 1970 Mar-Dec (Box Box 32)
        - Galax and Martinsville, 1970 Mar-Dec (Box Box 32)
        - Halifax, Henry, and Mecklenburg Counties, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 32)
        - Patrick and Pittsylvania Counties, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 33)
        - South Boston, 1969 Nov-1970 Dec; (2 folders) (Box Box 33)
      - Sixth District
        - Amherst, Bedford, and Botetourt Counties, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 33)
        - Bedford and Clifton Forge, 1970 Mar-Dec (Box Box 33)
        - Covington, 1970 Mar-Dec (Box Box 33)
        - Craig and Floyd Counties, 1970 Mar-Sep (Box Box 33)
        - Lynchburg, 1970 Mar-Nov; (2 folders) (Box Box 33)
        - Montgomery, Nelson, and Roanoke Counties, 1970 Mar-Oct (Box Box 34)
        - Radford, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 34)
        - Roanoke, 1970 Mar-Nov; (3 folders) (Box Box 34)
        - Salem, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 34)
      - Seventh District
        - Albemarle, Augusta, and Bath Counties, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 34)
        - Buena Vista, 1970 Apr-Sep (Box Box 34)
        - Charlottesville, 1970 Mar-Nov; (3 folders) (Box Box 35)
        - Clarke, Culpeper, and Fluvanna Counties, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 35)
        - Frederick, Greene, and Highland Counties, 1970 Mar-Oct (Box Box 35)
        - Harrisonburg, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 35)
        - Lexington, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 35)
        - Madison, Orange, and Page Counties, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 36)
        - Rappahannock, Rockbridge, and Rockingham Counties, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 36)
        - Shenandoah and Warren Counties, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 36)
        - Staunton, 1970 Mar-Oct (Box Box 36)
        - Waynesboro, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 36)
        - Winchester, 1970 Mar-Nov; (2 folders) (Box Box 36)
      - Eighth District
        - Caroline, Essex, and Fauquier Counties, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 37)
        - Fredericksburg, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 37)
        - Goochland, Hanover, and King & Queen Counties, 1970 Mar-Dec (Box Box 37)
        - King George, King William, and Lancaster Counties, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 37)
        - Loudoun County, 1970 Mar-Dec (Box Box 37)
        - Louisa, New Kent, and Northumberland Counties, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 37)
        - Prince William County, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 38)
        - Richmond, Spotsylvania, Stafford, and Westmoreland Counties, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 38)
      - Ninth District
        - Bristol, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 38)
        - Bland, Buchanan, Dickenson, Giles, and Lee Counties, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 38)
        - Norton, 1970 Nov 21 (Box Box 38)
        - Pulaski, Russell, Scott, and Smyth Counties, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 38)
        - Tazewell County, 1970 Mar-Oct (Box Box 38)
        - Washington, Wise, and Wythe Counties, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 38)
      - Tenth District
        - Alexandria, 1970 Mar-Nov; (5 folders) (Box Box 39)
        - Arlington County - A-J, 1970 Mar-Nov; (3 folders) (Box Box 39)
        - Arlington County - K-Z, 1970 Mar-Nov; (3 folders) (Box Box 40)
        - Fairfax City, 1970 Mar-Nov (Box Box 40)
        - Fairfax County, 1970 Mar-Dec; (4 folders) (Box Box 40)
        - Falls Church, 1970 Mar-Dec; (2 folders) (Box Box 41)
    - 2). Management Files
      - Announcement of Candidacy, 1970 Mar 17 (Box Box 41)
      - Board of Elections, 1970 Apr-Dec (Box Box 41)
      - Campaign Managers, 1970 (Box Box 41)
      - Campaign Materials, 1967-1970 (Box Box 41)
      - Congratulation Letters, 1970 Nov-Dec; (4 folders) (Box Box 41)
        Correspondents include: Alan Cranston; Albertis S. Harrison, Jr.; Hubert H. Humphrey; Daniel K. Inouye (telegram); Edward M. Kennedy; Jennings Randolph; Charles Percy; and Richard Schweiker
      - Contribution Thank-You Letters: A-L, 1970; (5 folders) (Box Box 42)
      - Contribution Thank-You Letters: Mc-Z, 1970; (7 folders) (Box Box 43)
      - Correspondence: Out-of-State, 1970 Mar-Nov; (5 folders) (Box Box 44)
        Correspondents include: Bernard M. Baruch, Jr.; Barry M. Goldwater; and Armand Hammer
      - Finance Committee, 1969-1971; (2 folders) (Box Box 44)
      - Finance Committee: Receipts for Contributions Not Acknowledged by Letter, 1970; (2 folders) (Box Box 45)
      - Invitations to Visit Senator Byrd, 1970; (3 folders) (Box Box 45)
      - Lists of Supporters, 1970; (2 folders) (Box Box 45)
      - Mims, Lathan D., 1970 Jan-Oct (Box Box 46)
      - Pending Invitations, 1970 Jun-Oct (Box Box 46)
      - Petitions, 1970 Jun (Box Box 46)
      - Pilots, 1970 Jul (Box Box 46)
      - Reports, 1970 Jun-Sep (Box Box 46)
      - Republicans for Byrd: Districts 1-6, 1970; (6 folders) (Box Box 46)
      - Republicans for Byrd: Districts 7-10, 1970; (5 folders) (Box Box 47)
      - Republican National Committee, 1970 (Box Box 47)
      - Thank-You Letters, 1970 Oct-Nov; (5 folders) (Box Box 48)
      - Thank-You Letters, 1970 Nov; (5 folders) (Box Box 49)
      - Vaden, Lewis(Treasurer), 1970 Feb (Box Box 49)
      - Voting Record of Senator Byrd, n.d. (Box Box 49)
    - 3). Publicity Files
      - Campaign Background, 1969-1970, n.d.; (2 folders) (Box Box 50)
      - Cargill, Wilson, & Acree Advertising Material and Reports, 1969 (Box Box 50)
      - Congressional Record Research on "No-Knock" Votes, 1970 (Box Box 50)
      - Conservative Voting Record, 1970 Oct 2 (Box Box 50)
      - Election Statistics and Run-off Returns, 1966-1970 (Box Box 50)
      - Endorsements for Harry F. Byrd, Jr., 1970 Jun (Box Box 50)
      - "Independent" Statement, 1970 Mar-Apr (Box Box 50)
      - Legislative Reference Service Questionnaire, 1969 Sep 5 (Box Box 50)
      - Media Campaign Technology Information, 1969-1970 (Box Box 50)
      - Miscellaneous Campaign Material, 1970-1971; (2 folders) (Box Box 51)
      - National Wholesale Druggists' Association, 1968, 1970 (Box Box 51)
      - Newsclippings & Press Releases, 1969-1970 (Box Box 51)
      - Position Papers, 1969, n.d. (Box Box 51)
      - Press - General, 1967-1969 (Box Box 51)
      - Primary Background and Reports, 1969-1970; (2 folders) (Box Box 51)
      - Radio and Television, 1970, n.d. (Box Box 51)
      - Speakers' Bureau, 1970 (Box Box 51)
      - Steering Committee, n.d. (Box Box 51)
      - Voter Survey by Oliver Quayle and Co., 1970 (Box Box 51)
- Series II: Speeches
  A Complete typed list of individual speech titles can be found in a spring-back binder in Box 61.
  - Speeches, 1965 Nov-1966 Apr 8; (6 folders) (Box Box 52)
  - Speeches, 1966 Apr 9-Jun 30; (7 folders) (Box Box 53)
  - Speeches, 1966 Jul-1967 Jul; (8 folders) (Box Box 54)
  - Speeches, 1967 Aug-1968 May; (7 folders) (Box Box 55)
  - Speeches, 1968 Jun-1969 Sep; (8 folders) (Box Box 56)
  - Speeches, 1969 Oct-1970 Apr; (7 folders) (Box Box 57)
  - Speeches, 1970 May-Oct; (6 folders) (Box Box 58)
  - Speeches, 1970 Nov-1971 Jul; (7 folders) (Box Box 59)
  - Speeches, 1971 Aug-1972 Feb; (6 folders) (Box Box 60)
  - Speeches, 1972 Mar-Dec; (6 folders) (Box Box 61)
- Series III: Legislative Files
  - Subseries A: General
    - Africa, 1967 Jul (Box Box 62)